So I find myself in the midst of a conversation that I genuinely am shocked is taking place.
And the reason why I'm shocked is taking place is because I genuinely find it surprising that so many folks that have followed my work for years,
that support my work, are insulted by the term cisgendered, CIS.
The reason why I am surprised by this is for a number of reasons.
One, because the term is not derogatory in any shape, way or form.
It actually is affirming.
The term CIS simply says that your sex organs and your chosen gender align with the way society has built out gender affirmation.
And that is, again, just the way society has built it out.
In this society, gender is still not as fluid as it actually is amongst the people who live in this society.
That being said, what it means is that your sex organs are female and that you identify as a woman.
That's simply what cisgendered means.
To me, this should make great sense to folks who are saying, you know, I'm the original woman.
I'm a full woman.
I'm a real woman.
You know, at the end of the day, the thing about the consideration of womanhood is that it is broad.
It is wide.
It is expansive.
And that to me is what's so beautiful about being a woman.
Is that we have had to, in so many ways, define our own identities in a world that has consistently made an effort to tell us what we are.
And when we look at the ways in which we exist, so many of us can share in things beyond our physical attributes into more of our spiritual attributes.
You know, as a woman, one of the things that we are commonly aligned with is our ability to nurture.
And that ability to nurture is something that I don't think we are living in when we are ostracizing others who are within the same space.
There is room.
When we live in a mindset of abundance, we understand that there is room.
When we live in a mindset of love, we understand there is room.
We also understand that as the world changes, as things grow, as we expand, we must expand, not just our minds, but we must expand our language.
We must expand our understanding.
That is about abundance.
When we talk about expansion, we're not talking about limitation.
I understand the feeling that being labeled cis makes you somehow an other, because now you have a label as well as this other group.
But I want us to consider the idea that it's not a label to make you an other.
It's a label that shows that you are another.
And when we consider that, we say, oh, I am not the only.
And there is nothing limiting your identity as a woman by saying that there are other ways that people can also be women.
That's beautiful to me.
And so when we say to ourselves, I don't want to be called cis because they are trying to take away my womanhood, we're not thinking in abundance.
We're thinking in scarcity and we're thinking in limitation.
And we need to be honestly thinking about how can we have more.
I would love to have more women.
Because as women, we know that we are in a world that needs more of us to be running shit.
Because when we do, we change things.